<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Building Packet Spy</title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Building Packet Spy">
            <p>
                Packet Spy is made up of a native library and a java
                interface. Unfortunately there is no single build process
                as Make and/or Visual Studio is used to build the native
                component and Maven is used to build the java library,
                distribution and documentation. You can download the source
                as per the instructions on the
                <a href="downloads.html">downloads</a> page.
            </p>
            <p>
                The following libraries and/or tools were used to build
                Packet Spy. They must be downloaded and installed prior
                to building Packet SPy.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Apache Maven 1.0-RC2. Download from <a href="http://maven.apache.org">http://maven.apache.org</a>.</li>
                <li>Sun 1.4.2_04 JDK (under Windows)</li>
                <li>WinPCap 3_1_beta_3 (under Windows)</li>
                <li>Blackdown 1.4.1 JDK (under Linux)</li>
                <li>Libpcap 0.8 (under Linux)</li>
            </ul>
            <p>
                The include files and library files of the pcap library and the
                jdk must be made available to the Packet Spy build process. This
                can be done by either modifying <code>src/make/Makefile</code>
                (under Linux) or by adding the paths to the VC++ Directories
                configuration (under Windows).
            </p>
            <p>
                The first step is to type <code>maven</code> in command line
                in the the base directory. This will compile the java library
                and generate c headers for inclusion in the native library.
                Then you need to build the native component either via
                <code>cd src/make; make</code> (under Linux) or via loading and
                building the <code>src/make/dot.net/packetspy.sln</code> Solution
                into Visual Studio (under Windows). The last step is to run
                <code>maven</code> again as this will rename the native library
                to the name expected by the compiled java library. At this point
                you should have a complete build for your platform. Congratulations!
            </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
